hello and welcome to CIO leadership live in asan
my name is sharine Robert editor of asan based
in Singapore and we're back for another episode
in conversation with it leaders across southeast
Asia and Hong Kong around leadership Innovation
and business strategy today I'm joined by San
Pand group Chief technology and operations officer
of FWD Insurance in Hong Kong welcome sand thank
you sharim it's it's it's a pleasure to be with
you today awesome um so just to give yourself an
opportunity to introduce yourself to our audience
um maybe share a bit more about the role that
you have um it's a really long title so give some
insight into what actually you do on a day-to-day
thank you yes as as my title says I look after the
technology and operations as you know I have I've
been in the technology uh for quite some time and
I also done country operations role in my previous
experiences as well so just introducing myself
I'm the group Chief technology and operations
officer for FWD and what does that mean is I'm
responsible for the customer the operations as
well as um you know the technology for FWB From
endtoend perspective group wide across all the
10 markets we operate in and you know if you
see predominantly my experience I started from
manufacturing of course I started from fmcg and
then I moved into um Financial Services uh you
know way back in 20 early 2000s from you know AIG
to AIA and bua and now FWD and it is always been I
I'm so excited to see how insurance industry has
really transformed in the last 15 20 years where
technology has really become a center stage of uh
you know the driving the business strategy as well
right so that has always been the uh thing which
has driven me so in in my current uh you know the
role I look at the customer operations from end to
end perspective and what does that mean insing is
like how do we we are very passionate if you know
our vision is to change the way people feel about
insurance so I'm very passionate about how do we
create uh the 360 of customer experience which
I talk about the customer experience side of it
because we're a customer Le company the also the
distribution experience because our agents Bank
Partners Brokers everybody is important and last
but not least is also the employ experience side
of it so so we need to look at all three sides
of the customer experience in my view and then we
should be creating those Solutions which cater to
our end customer also our uh employe experience
as well as for our distribution uh you asked me
what does your day look like so of course on
a on a day-to-day basis it's all about so I
bucket uh every one of us our leaders role in two
buckets enabling the growth and uh looking at the
operational efficiency right because we need to
do both so of course uh you know insurance is a
sales-driven organization so you have to actively
sell insurance and we need to enable that and that
brings the growth that brings the protection that
brings the you know the savings product through
our channels but of course we need to also operate
efficiently and that brings the simplification
side of it you know the agility side of it and we
will talk some of the things I'm sure about cloud
and how some of the new Texs are enabling that
so you know to be honest on a day-to-day basis
I engage with businesses a lot really understand
we have a clear threeyear you know the technology
and operations strategy in align with our business
strategy and and day-to-day basis my role would be
around ensuring U are we actively listening to our
customers uh what are the things which are coming
in large programs how are they progressing how's
Employee Engagement sentiments are and so on and
so forth right so that that to me is is what uh
my role involves on day-to-day basis you're kind
of in a unique position um in terms of managing
both technology and people um especially having
such a close relationship with customers of in an
organization that is really about um making sure
customers benefit from you know the products that
you're selling um I I'm curious to know as as I
Was preparing for our chat today I was learning
a bit more about you know your experience your
background uh and as you mentioned you've been
um in the insurance sector for quite a some time
now and um primarily managing technology um so
in in your mind in your view how have you seen
technology evolved across the years um and
currently how does that impact the way you
execute strategies that's a great question I think
technology if even if you you know go back from
Industrial Age to our you know the information
age to the you know the U then now we are in Ai
and gen Age Technology has always enable people to
become more uh efficient right for example right
so you know manufacturing process for example
has already always got automated in Insurance
Financial Services as well the things are on
paper your your requirement to have that paperless
experience for example your requirement to have
that you know the quick turnaround time when we
submit a servicing request or a caims request
your requirement to ensure that I give you a
personalized experience uh you know in a in a more
simplified way and I cut through the I cut through
the uh red tape quickly and you know get to where
you want to get to as a as a customer rather than
having to go through so many screens and so many
things has been the evolution the evolution has
been also moving away from paper based transaction
to really digital based experience or in the last
you know the Advent of uh all this uh digital age
and digital insurance as you know we have been we
have been bagging digital insurer of the year
for quite some time and we but we need to and
we cater to all segment ments sh it's not just
a particular segment so the solutioning which
we have to do needs to be catering to all stret of
our uh customers not just not just for that matter
genz or or or um uh you know genx has to be old
right so that that's so that brings to the fact
that and technology has Evol and today we take
smartphone as as for granted like you know so
it's it's a computer in your hand literally it has
everything you do and spend a lot of time there so
technology has evolved a lot in the last uh 15 20
years and so has the insurance industry embracing
that technology has also evolved uh you know gone
on those days where Insurance used to be a lagger
you know it used to be behind uh you know the
banking industry I would argue that the Innovation
which have happened in the last 15 years in
insurance is happened far more faster and at the
pace uh you know in and which is what is exciting
so I've seen lot of those ins Transformations have
happened through this uh you know the digital
transformation and honestly speaking we are
as good as our if our customers really like that
experience then it makes sense for example you can
invest in all kind of Technology all kind of these
uh digital tools but if they don't use it if they
don't experience it and if they don't appreciate
it it's of no point another thing which I feel has
also we don't talk much about is having the should
uplift in place shoting right so for example
infrastructure as a code Cloud Transformations
like you know I would say information security
which are normally taken for granted is this
also gone through a huge transformation over
the last uh you know the I would say last 15 20
years because the threat actors are changing it
is becoming more they becoming more sophisticated
your that Landscapes are changing so you have to
look at technology from end to- end perspective
you have to look at from your fundamentals how
do you look at that informational security and
then creating those the the CX the DX and also
the employee experience which I talk about and
what are those digital tools which is going to
move the nle to enable both the growth as well as
the operational efficiency which we need to look
at I hope that makes sense yeah and I definitely
agree with the approach I especially love the
part about you know leaving no customer behind
I'm sure my parents my grandparents generation
would app appreciate that a lot especially
because um in this technology age where it's
also advancing really quick um it's tough for
them to keep up um they've come from a time
where all these digital tools did not exist where
they were going to make an insurance claim it was
going to their trusted advisor you know to seek
that to seek that kind of application process and
things like that um so it's entirely different um
experience by them right now U and we'll get into
a bit more about you know how you're meeting those
customer expectations very customer expectations
you know um dat on in this conversation um but
first I wanted to focus a bit more on that club
transformation that you were speaking about uh for
FWD how has that um Journey been like um and how
it given the time that you've had to implement and
also see the results of it where where do you see
it impacting the business the most another great
question sing I think you got a list of all great
questions today I'm sure so Cloud for us from
the beginning was a holistic business strategy
and that's where we differentiate it was not just
a technology strategy right from the beginning the
commitment from all the way from our you know the
board to the top management and to the businesses
were always there so about three three and a half
years ago when I came in I saw that opportunity
to say you know what if you really want to be
the the customer light company which we we are
we need to make sure that we're quickly moving and
embracing these uh you know the ad advancement of
uh Cloud which is happening having your workload
in data center is not being able to give you that
efficiency and that I'm I'm not just talking
about the cost efficiency but the scale the
stability and the experience of year after and
also the turnaround times right so your speed
to Market your way to ensure that we are able to
spin off uh you know the workloads and switch it
off when we don't need demand based that workload
is very important and most important thing when
we started this uh cloud transformation Journey
shooting we were at the right at the center of
covid right as you can see and imagine if you
didn't have that kind of a you know enablement
for our you know staff to work remotely enablement
for our distribution and for our customers to be
able to interact with us uh seamlessly it would
have become another challenge right so you trying
to get servers during that time it would have
been months before you could you could get uh
any any workload so it has enabled our business
to be resilient it has enabled our business to be
continue to focus on what we want to do for
our customers but also ensuring that we are
embracing these advancements in the in the cloud
transformation which has been happening so when
we started in December 2021 we were at like 20 we
were like 27% today we are at 97% on cloud right
so we have done the rapid uh deployment into cloud
and not like living any any again you know markets
behind so we have done if you look at across our
markets our markets are 0 90% at least each of the
markets up and certain markets are even 100%
on Cloud for example right so that's been our
Cloud transformation Journey the differentiation
I always make uh sharen is that your Tech strategy
has to be 100% aligned with your business strategy
and if we are looking at changing the way people
feel about insurance we want to enable that growth
we want to be customer Le company we want want to
create a differentiated experience then we got
to have the cloud infrastructure in the back end
already transformed and our Cloud transformation
was not just about lifting and shifting
applications to the cloud it was also about
actually transforming modernizing and getting
rid of those old applications while we were doing
that 33% of our application as state is completely
decommissioned modernized as a virtue in the
last three years so we actually removed you know
the number of applications of 33% of our entire
applications to actually get that uh so we had two
clear kpis we Al we wanted to do Cloud adoption or
what we call it as a you know the cloud adoption
kpi but also application rationalization kpi
which means we need to modernize our applications
as well on not just lift and shift uh to the to
the um thr data center to to Cloud because that's
going to increase the cost we all know that if you
just remove lift and shift so that's why we were
very conscious about doing it the right from the
beginning putting that business strategy alignment
how it is going to enable product turnaround times
how it is going to enable my in resiliency uh you
know stability scalability how it is going to
ensure that I have that distinct competitive
Advantage but also most important of it Al that
it is efficiently run once it is gone into the
the cloud we have done Cloud finops to make sure
that you know they be constantly looking at how
the workloads are managed on the cloud as well so
sorry for having more detailed uh you know answers
on that but I think it's important for audience
to understand that you know it's a driving a cloud
transformation is very different from on paper to
actually executing it and we we very clear from
the beginning that we going to have a multicloud
strategy U so we have our two key Cloud sour so
every brand available out there but definitely
we had AWS as well as Azure two key providers
on our our cloud and so we were very clear
like you know so arguably people will say
that oh I have multicloud but if you go around
and see 90 to 95% of their workload will be on
just one of the cloud providers we are really
very different we are truly multicloud and you
know our workloads are roughly une equally
divided between the two workload it gives us
bit of uh you again resilience among the cloud
providers we don't want to put all our eggs in
our one basket it also gives us I would say
the negotiation and and Competitive Edge in
terms of ensuring that the you know the both the
key Cloud providers are interested and giving us
that kind of U attention which we need uh
because we can never forget sharing that
we are a regulated business we are a regulated
business in each market so another key important
thing is that even The Regulators have really
become very Progressive or the in the last 10
years as you can see they are they're looking at
how uh Insurance Industries are going to embrace
this and keep still our pdpa uh responsibility
our data security responsibility information
security responsibility and with that with Cloud
it becomes much better because your visibility
becomes better your ability to protect it and and
and uh deliver it faster becomes uh better and of
course you need to keep on uh protecting it and
your layer security micro segmentation those all
become very important uh so see it's also about
execution right so making sure that our regulatory
requirements are fulfilled making sure that we
do not have any thinkk taken for granted in each
market not just in Hong Kong but in Singapore in
Malaysia in Indonesia and making sure we have both
sides of the regulations Tak care so that was our
Focus of course last but not least on the cloud
also becomes very important is the talent because
everybody is going to fight for the same Talent so
how do you ensure that so we launched Technology
Academy two years plus ago to make sure that our
skills are upskills and reskilled internally to
take care of that so you need to take care of
all elements of it the strategy side of it the
implementation side of it business alignment
side of it also making sure how it's going to be
proof points based kpi Le but also are people led
because ultimately you need rights at of people
to be able to to manage that uh you know from
end to end perspective so that has been our Cloud
transformation Journey which I'm very proud of the
team in the group as well as in the markets for
the achievements we have had and we have a lot
of accredition from uh you know the industry for
for for doing it differently for doing it at speed
and also been a very good good success story for
for us at at trid and you're absolutely right with
the devils in the details I'm sure you have
taken the time to you know put thought careful
thought into how you want to actually combine
the best set of tools and infrastructure and
people in the process all in one you know to
create this um journey and transformation um
and as you mentioned you you manage 10 different
markets 10 very different markets um which would
have their own set of you know um cultures people
process technology um how do you see technology
operations and adoption differ among the markets
that you operate um and if yes why do you think
it differs in in vastly in vast ways or not um
and in Your Capacity how do you close the gaps
so that you can offer you know that sense of
UniFi and senors experience that both employees
and customers across the board like cine that's
that's again great question so I think from the
I I'm been very fortunate to be able to work in
the group office roles as well as in the markets
roles so if you see I worked in Hong Kong market
I've worked in Singapore I've worked in Malaysia
market so I've been able to appreciate both sides
of the coin very you know uh quickly because
sometimes you have never worked in group office
you would you would always say that I don't know
why group is trying to do they don't understand
the market perspective but if you have also never
worked in Market you think that this is your paint
of glass and everybody needs to follow that so it
comes to me very naturally uh to me to be honest
and that's why that's what I uh actually push my
leadership team to is that we have to understand
and think from from both perspective so we just
don't do a top down strategy Sharin we also do
the bottom up so we go to I went to every Market
CEOs every Market CTO to say hey this is what
the technology strategy or op strategy should
look like what do you think and then they say oh
in in Philippines Market some we need to look at
this in Singapore Market you need to look at that
so we collected every On's I would say the voices
and ensure that we refresh and we go back to them
and close the loop I'm a huge fan of closing the
loop I do not like things to be open dangling out
there right so even if I have delegated something
I would always like to make sure that that that
piece of uh thing was closed so same way here so
we we just not do one time collection of the input
and just roll out the strategy we again go back
and back and back and make sure that after that
it is our strategy so today we don't talk about
the technology strategy as is group technology
strategy is from great it is our strategy so if
you go to Philippines you see the same strategy if
you go to Indonesia you see the same uh you know
Tech and on strategy but of course the apis are
specific for the market they you know there are
there is a notar and there's a you know the group
like this which we need to uh you know achieve but
as starting point would be different and we need
to be appreciative of your earlier point of the
culture a Japan uh Works in a very different
way versus Hong Kong versus Singapore so you
need to be able to look at your people process
and Tech all the three elements of it to create
that solution and it's not one siiz fit all as
well sh so when we create Solutions I like to
always give this notion of you'll hear a lot about
one modularity which is becoming another unique
from our side A lot of people are asking me
about one modularity is because truly making
your back and architecture modular what does that
mean that means that I really have a stack 1 to
10 just to give an example and ultimately
we are Insurance business right so 1 to S
would be common for example either we're in the
protection business or we're in the savings so
that fundamentals of insurance servicing
claims new business will remain the same
but the way I do that selling in Singapore
for example if I'm 100% digital The Experience
would be different or through ifas and broker LS
versus agency versus Bank assurance that would be
different and and the solution which I built needs
to cater to these differentiations of the market
and that's why I say it is 1 to7 we built as as
a common stack and Lead that flexibility of 8910
for Market by market to have that customization
so that when you go to Indonesia not just the
language requirements in this like or Hong Kong
both and even Japan but also the experience is
consistent in line with what a Japanese customer
would expect it's in line with consistent with
what a Malaysian customer would you know
expect and so on and so forth so having that
appreciation the cultural appreciation having that
switched on mindset of we all are different and we
to create that cohesive uh you know consistent
Tech and this solutioning but experience must be
catering to the customers in each market and that
has been our success story our success story is
not one siiz fo all we take the commonalities of
course we need to be efficient I told you so we
need to build that 1 to7 common stack it will be
crazy to have 10 different customer portal looking
in in 10er markets it'll be crazy to have 10
different Journeys in 10 markets it crazy to have
different distribution uh you know the uh Tools
in 10 different markets and that's what we have
been after we've been after to get platform Le
mindset rather than applet mindset so we have our
the distribution platform is C our the customer
platform is only our the operations platform is
Opus and enabling all these three platform is the
modularized architecture which I call it as one
modularity so that's what we are driving uh our
organization towards to bring that consistency
of experience bring that efficiency and also 100%
business alignment because then everybody can move
towards that common goal because at the end of the
day it's all about customer we are a customer Le
company and it's all about customer at the end
of the day and if we are as good as if we have
created anything and if our customers are not
feeling it you as a customer Shing if you don't
feel that differentiated experience when you come
to FWD uh and doesn't matter whether you TI talk
to FWD agent or through your bank or through our
website or our application you got to get that you
know differentiated experience and we've been
very proud we get a lot of these social media
posts even The Regulators uh post it uh when they
experience us uh you know versus the other but we
don't sit on our Laurels we constantly going back
and challenging ourselves so so hopefully it gives
you a more rounded uh answer around how really it
needs to work yeah yeah and I have to say s it's
tough it's tough to create that personalization
um that localization strategy even uh but it
seems that you're on the right track in terms
of finding that recipe that works for you of
you know establishing a group strategy but also
giving that space um and Authority on the ground
itself for your individual leaders um to you know
further explore and expand on do how they like
to self their customers um and I I hug on the
customers a lot because like you mentioned you
are a very strong customer basing business um and
from our own um insights as well we see customer
expectations are growing um tremendously and like
you mentioned also um the Gen Z the Millennials um
they have their own ideas of what they like out
of you know the service that they they perceive
and receive um from you know where they they shop
um and in terms of FWD service expectations and
service experience um what do you what are you
actually sharing from customers or what they
would like more out of you guys and what is how
do you kind of marry technology with that you know
creating that Technology support to deliver really
strong customer outcomes yeah so like I said we're
a customer Le company and we are looking we
always look at what we call it as a customer
engagement and experience uh survey which we do
independently done by KPMG for us every year to
look at the customer experience score for Market
by market what are the voice of the customers we
do from time to time the VOC surveys to ensure
that we stay true to what we are saying from a
customer angle right not just what we think that
we are good or not in 2022 um all our markets our
customers have either rated us good or great right
so that's for example last year also we had a very
good rating the market uh for but again as we back
into future we also looking at how do we take it
to the next level so not all markets at the same
level to be to be honest right uh and we need to
bring every Market to be at least at the same
uh you know a minimum standard for example and
that's where our Focus has been we want to create
solutions for all markets where we are in the in
the higher top topper end of the percentile on
getting the whether STP stdu which is straight to
processing straight to underwriting digital eded
option digital adoption we are already um higher
90s right so for me um how do we then take it to
the next level of straight to processing NPS like
claims NPS we are across the group if you look at
we are 84% Plus on claims NPS for example on our
you know the customer app but we want to bring
that across the board for all our businesses
and um we need to bring all markets to the same
level certain markets we are doing extremely well
certain markets we are still not there and that's
where that's where our focus is I just a follow up
on that so um in terms of how different markets
are you know perceiving technology differently
as well U customers are also pursuing technology
differently and we we spoke about it a bit earlier
about how you know different Generations see it
differently and um some maybe are a bit unsure
of you how they would be able to adapt um so how
would FWD make it easier for customers to adapt
to technology as it grows as quickly as it can
possibly can yeah we have a we have a famous uh
philosophy of uh three steps if you're not able to
get to where you want to get into the three steps
then we need to go back and look at the experience
for example so if you're if you're coming there
and if you're quickly and it could be as simple
as ask an agent to call so it doesn't have to
be like uh you know take you through the the full
Journey if you're a gen Z and and and and geni 40
45% of our our you know customer base are in that
category for example right and and is growing at
the same time I think it's in the 60s 60 person
now but that goes to show that we are not leaving
any anybody behind like I I told you but at the
same time if you are um our Parish generation
who wants to speak to someone I want to enable
that but I don't want to speak to a person but
I want to speak to a bot I need to enable that for
example certain cultures are shy they do not like
to speak to to people they they rather speak to to
to a bot they are more more happy about speaking
to a bot so how do we enable that for example but
it could not be a traditional bot of FAQs Le it
has to be able to and that's where we will get
into Ai and generative AI Le you know the voice
BS for example so it's actually giving you more ex
personalized or experience-based uh conversation
uh rather than uh you know just and making it
easy for example sometimes I want to speak to
the human I don't want to mention I was just in
Thailand and one of the social media post was
from our regulator was that the regulator called
up another insurer and they asked and the person
picked up and they asked them so many questions
uh before they can get just the answer about the
details of what what the person was looking for
and when they call FWD it was picked up by our
AI uh chat it asked just the last three four digit
of the national ID and quickly it gave the answer
what um you know the regulator was looking for so
now these are the testament which we get directly
from our Regulators Hong Kong ma U last year I
remember posted that you know literally within
within seconds the uh the money was banked into
the uh you know the account not just so we believe
in instant claims not just instant processing
so if you come through our app and we know that
you have passed through all our rules quickly we
just don't tell you that oh you know the claims
have been done is actually the money in in your
bank that's what you see and that's what again
last year one of the regulator had posted that
guys it is true that the money has come in my
bank not just just the straight to processing so
I think how do we push the envelope to go to the
next level uh from our parents generation to the
you know the Baby Boomers to geny to Gen X it has
to cater to everyone and it needs to understand
and you should be able to get your profile and
understand what you're looking for like I said
quickly so I'm looking for this thing and I I give
you that preference quickly to say do you want to
speak to someone do you want to speak to uh to our
chatbot or do you want to speak uh and you want
to just do dat yourself service for example so we
don't leave anything uh so we look at everything
so it's not just this or that based on what you
want and how quickly you get it right so we are
very passionate about what what am I looking
for am I looking for a product information am I
looking for servicing request or I'm looking for
somebody to speak to I should be able to get to
that customer needs pretty quickly also financial
literacy as you know in this part of the world we
have to constantly focus on financial Wellness not
just physical and mental Wellness which we are
we are passionate about how do we look at your
financial literacy so for example your financial
needs analysis so you come to our you know portals
or app and your ability to be able to do financial
needs analysis or through our agents if you sit
through our agents or our bank Insurance Channel
they take you through a proper financial needs
analysis so that we avoid any Miss selling we
avoid any overselling so we need to make sure
that this is the right product for you and then
we sell it uh you know the right thing for you but
also giving you that option that people like you
so our AI for example um you know the tool gives
you the production score and tells you people
like you were looking for these things as well
are you interested for example so ultimately like
I said we are a sales demand organization but not
at the it's a difference between overselling and
being on your face versus a a really meaningful
nudges and if you're interested we take you to the
next level and if you're not interested we leave
you rather than being hounding on your face and
you have to buy you have to buy you have to buy
that's not we are after we wanting to create that
differentiated experience but if you're willing to
if you don't want to go through that journey and
want to quickly get to I want to speak to someone
I should have that option I should not force you
that no you have to complete this journey before
you speak to anybody else so that's that's where
we create differently and certain businesses for
example Philipp means uh people prefer mobile
they do not prefer laptop or computers uh laptop
computers or or iPads or or you know Android
pads so we created Solutions which are craving
you the same experience you know stre but on a
mobile device so it should not be just take that
portal or iPad and and dump it into the mobile
uh you know uh frame but it's actually really red
defining the experience if you're going through
uh uh your mobile device which is shorter even if
you have the pro Max or something your experience
and journey has to be catering to that rather than
saying that oh I converted the same 10 pages and
now I have just put it on the mobile phone which
will be a very clunky experience because you every
time you have to zoom out zoom in that's not we
are doing so we reimagine every time this happens
we work with our digital team uh and we reimagine
the journeys and then ensure that the back end
is delivering that differentiated experience
and again I don't need to build three times that
thing so it's also important that remember what
I said about being efficient so how do we create
Landing zones so that we create the code ones and
deploy into various uh not just the Frameworks or
the mobile frames to iPad frames to uh you know
the website but also truly having a same piece of
code working into into in a different kind of uh
uh you know devices and that's where you will
bring efficiency otherwise if you imagine if
your development team has to do three different
sets of development one for laptop one for this
one for that it's again you're not efficient so
you have to embrace technology internally make it
efficient and that should be evident through your
customer experience and it's all about your voice
of customer and as I I kept saying End customer
distri bution Channel as well as employees all
three must tell us that yes this is delivering
the uh efficiency we are after once again we're
going back to that level of personalization
that you're creating for customers giving them
choices which all of us like um and you're also
covering fwd's back by giving FWD choices as well
for the team to R um decide that they have this
variety of tools to deploy um and really create
a simless experience all around for both end
selfie organization um and you raised the point
a about AI so I had to ask you about AI um so in
your mind um I assume you will be exploring AI um
already um but what are the some of the use cases
that you are specifically seeing in the market or
experimenting with yourself and how would FWD
um roll out a viable news case um and what are
the intended outcomes you like to see I would
say I would like to add the word responsible
AI again remember we are a regulated business
and we are very responsible for our customers
so I just don't talk about AI I talk about
responsible AI so we that's that is at the
you know the core of everything when we look at
as of you know I would say even so it's not the
new thing since 2019 we've been looking at Ai
and we have integrated it through like I said
like you know our production score people like
you in know automator underwriting we have ai
like underwriting we have app some of the things
now we're looking at AI claims so that we are able
to get to these I would say meaningful outcomes
as we speak in fact as of 2022 we already have
more than 600 use cases and 200 AI models and in
2024 now since last one year since generative AI
we're moving the needle not just from AI not to
look at generative Ai and how the generative AI
has really advanced in the just last one year and
that's going back to our initial conversation of
how industry not just the industry is changing how
the technology transformation will happen and if
you see Google's or Microsoft or even AWS talking
about this piece of revolution is fastest so far
in our human you know civilization so how do we be
out there but perform in a responsible way because
it also has its own uh you know the dangers of it
right for example so how do we have a so we have
a AI Council or we call it as a AI subcommittee to
look at all our AI models and ensure that those AI
models have been implemented in a responsible way
are governed not just talked about so we worked
with the second line as well as the third line
and we have a independent AI subcommittee we have
a technology risk subcommittee which talks about
cyber security information security but also we
have separate dedicated AI subcommittee which
is run by our compliance team and we are part
of that to look at every AI models which we have
implemented so far it is done in possible way and
we have a proper governance around it so I think
that's and but we have been embracing we already
have uh 600 use cases what we are excited about
now we're looking at into the future is fraud
detection for example claims fraud detection uh
our ability to process lot set of data through the
large language model quickly that's what we are of
to say are specific achievements we have achieved
around the claims detection now we're looking at
claims the whole claims efficiency itself right
so for example our claims as a how do we how do
then give them more deeper Insight quickly through
our generative AI so that the decisions can be
made in a faster way but also in a meaningful
way so I think these are the some of the specific
examples where we are after but we are looking at
generative AI in every aspects of our business
we're looking from a new business perspective
from our distribution to kitp perspective on
our Omni by FWD for example we have now you
know created those avatars which are generative
AI Le which helps you uh look at some of those
experiences very differently not just Miry where
you take a picture and it tells you what's your
health uh condition is but also making it slightly
more different not just not just fun but really
engaging in in our platform so we're looking
at generative AI on all angles from a customer
servicing claims perspective on new business side
perspective and processing large set of data for
example uh perspective but also looking at virtual
avatars and how it can enable you to engage with
us better and I gave you some specific examples
where we have already started to see results and
those are some very interesting but also necessary
areas where you're kind of implementing AI um I
for myself we about to pick a Insurance CL I
would definitely want to you know ensure it's
a fast and I would say enjoyable process in a way
um you know I don't want to stress about you know
making a claim um or being concerned that you
know it won't come in you know um so if the
company can ensure that it's a better process it's
it's comforting to know that I can trust you know
you guys um and especially because you need to
position yourselves as trusted advisers that's
all the more important why you need to have the
right technology in place that we cannot forget
so we always talk about digital heart with
human touch that human aspects of insurance
we cannot forget ultimately when God forbid you
have a you know when you have a outpatient and
and minor claims is fine but when you have death
claims we need to handle that with the sensitivity
as well so it's not just about okay I gave you
the digital experience but I also give you FWD
care so we have FWD care for example which is our
entire end to end um you know the claims handling
as an attach which we give it to our our customers
in few markets and you know where we take care
of you throughout the whole journey rather than
just saying that okay your claims got processed
and here is the check but also about where is how
is your mental state um you know do you need some
help there do you want to speak to someone and
do you you know so again not being intervening
Again by being very culturally sensitive but also
if you need me we here so that human element of
insurance is what keeps me in this business so I'm
not just about all the fancy tools and and digital
experience only but also what is that human
aspects ultimately we humans for a reason our
responsibility to create the better world for our
next Generation cannot go away our responsibility
to ensure that on a day-to-day basis we do
not ex we do not forget the human element of
it I'm very passionate about these things right
so when we create Solutions we make need to make
sure that the human touch is equally important
seeing so we don't want to be a cold company
which is just bunch of robots which are doing all
the things and no feeling and even with generative
you can have emotions in that but humans are human
and that human touch but we are very proud of our
digital uh you know the advancement and experience
but we always say digital heart for human touch
that's the perfect way to end our conversation and
it was the reason why I thought it was such um it
would be powerful to have you speak on we know
both technology and people since you handle both
of those um elements in um FWD uh so thank you so
much for giving us an Insight Peak into your role
and of course the many complex projects that you
spear haed and are spear haing for FWD I and to
our audience I hope you enjoyed this episode and
we'll see you again next time thank you so much
thank you so much for having me today and you
know it's it's an honor like you know whenever
your world gets expanded it's always an honor
for us to be able to serve for our customers I
hope you are our customer I hope you also get
that experience too Sharin it was absolutely a
pleasure and great set of questions so thank you
for having me today just all by thank you so much